Guide to the Hans Bethe papers, ca. 1931-1995
Bethe, Hans papers,
- Series VI. History
  - Subseries I. General
    - Shelter Island II, (n.d.) (Box 46, Folder 55)
      Includes photocopies of notes from Bethe provided by Silvan Schweber on the 1947 Shelter Island conference. See https://ecommons.cornell.edu/handle/1813/14146
    - Shelter Island II, 1982-1983 (Box 46, Folder 56)
    - Congressional Testimony, 1982-1985 (Box 46, Folder 57)
    - Articles on Hist., 1982-1987 (Box 46, Folder 58)
    - History of science materials, 1982-1990 (Box 46, Folder 59)
    - Short papers [on Bethe], book reviews, 1982-1994 (Box 46, Folder 60)
    - General History. Judith Goodstein Interview, 1982-1999 (Box 46, Folder 61)
    - Memoranda, 1983 (Box 46, Folder 62)
    - Sommerfeld exhibit, catalog (Deutsches Museum), 1984 (Box 46, Folder 63)
    - Cornell Adult University, CAU, 1985 (Box 46, Folder 64)
    - History of Physics, S-matrix, 1985 (Box 46, Folder 65)
    - Niehls Bohr. Article for Indian Journal, 1985 (Box 46, Folder 66)
    - Proposal of Nobel for Lindhard, 1985 (Box 46, Folder 67)
    - Notes to and Ithaca Talk by Weizsaecker, 1987 (Box 46, Folder 68)
    - Ubell Correspond, 1987-1988 (Box 46, Folder 69)
    - Feynman, 1988 (Box 46, Folder 70)
    - McGeorge Bundy, German U project, 1988 (Box 46, Folder 71)
    - Rabi, 1988 (Box 46, Folder 72)
    - Viki, Pontifical, 1980-1988 (Box 46, Folder 73)
    - Viki, 1988 (Box 46, Folder 74)
    - Cornell Political Forum, 1989 (Box 46, Folder 75)
    - Dirac, 1989 (Box 46, Folder 76)
    - From a life of Physics, 1989 (Box 46, Folder 77)
    - Sakharov, 1989-1990 (Box 46, Folder 78)
    - List of Publications, 1990's (Box 46, Folder 79)
    - Bethe Cornell Biography, 1990 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Konopinski, 1990 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Memorial Articles, 1990-1991 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Nuclear pioneers petition, 1991 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Fermi, 10/14/91, 1991-1993 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Teller Biogr., 1992 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Los Alamos and Cornell, 1992 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Sam Schweber: draft on Feynman, history of QFT, (n.d.) (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Schweber: Quantum Chemistry history, (n.d.) (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Sam Schweber paper, 1982 (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Schweber, 1992 (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Schweber, 1993 (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - Sam [Schweber], 1998 (Box 47, Folder 13)
    - Reminiscences: Feynman, Vicki, 1993-1994 (Box 47, Folder 14)
    - Rudy, 1995 (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - Friedrich Hund, 1996 (Box 47, Folder 16)
    - Peierls, 1978 (Box 47, Folder 17)
    - Marshak Bio, Peierls, 1996 (Box 47, Folder 18)
    - Peierls' memorial service, 1996 (Box 47, Folder 19)
    - Peierls [Conference], 1997 (Box 47, Folder 20)
    - Peierls, U.C. Santa Barb., 1997 (Box 47, Folder 21)
    - Interview (Fowler), 2003 (Box 47, Folder 22)
    - Biography of R.F. Bacher, 2004 (Box 47, Folder 23)
    - Draft: 'My Life in Astrophysics [pub. 2003]', 2003 (Box 47, Folder 24)
    - Gerry Biography, 2003 (Box 47, Folder 25)
    - Bernstein, H-bomb, (n.d.) (Box 47, Folder 26)
    - Target Committee, 1945 (Box 47, Folder 27)
      -Meeting minutes discussing possible targets for "Little Boy" and "Fat Man", bombs dropped on Hiroshima and Nagasaki
    - Naturwiss, Teller article, 1984 (Box 47, Folder 28)
    - TV 1995-anniversary, 1995 (Box 47, Folder 29)
    - H-Bomb History, (n.d.) (Box 47, Folder 30)
    - H-bomb, 1950-2005 (Box 47, Folder 31)
    - Draft - HAB - History of the H-Bomb, 1954 (Box 47, Folder 32)
    - 'Progressive' again, 1979, 1980 (Box 47, Folder 33)
    - Talk: Making of Atom Bomb, 1988 (Box 47, Folder 34)
    - Brotherhood of the Bomb, 2002 (Box 47, Folder 35)
    - Hiroshima, 1982, 1990 (Box 47, Folder 36)
    - Columbia Physics Dept., (n.d.) (Box 47, Folder 37)
    - Max Born, Ewald, (n.d.) (Box 47, Folder 38)
    - Die Naturwissenschaften (Bethe), 1931 (Box 47, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence Peierls, 1938 (Box 47, Folder 40)
    - Conf. History Nuclear Physics. May 18-19, 1969, 1969 (Box 47, Folder 41)
    - Atomic Energy History; Hankins L.A., 1973 (Box 47, Folder 42)
    - Bethe Interview, Eisenhower Oral History Project, 1977 (Box 47, Folder 43)
    - Oral History Interview, Eisenhower Lib., 1977 (Box 47, Folder 44)
    - Minnesota Conference, nuclear physics history, 1977-1994 (Box 47, Folder 45)
    - Misc. History, 1979-1987 (Box 47, Folder 46)
    - Day after Trinity, 1981 (Box 47, Folder 47)
    - Interview with Hans Bethe, Cal-Tech, 1982 (Box 47, Folder 48)
    - Higinbotham, L.A.S.L, 1944-1945, 1990's (Box 47, Folder 49)
    - Story on Bethe, 1993 (Box 47, Folder 50)
    - Nagasaki/Hiroshima anniversary, 1995 (Box 47, Folder 51)
    - Misc. articles on sci history, 1995-1996 (Box 47, Folder 52)
    - Argonne N.L. Anniversary Colloquium: photos, 1996 (Box 47, Folder 53)
    - Gamow Symposium, 12 Apr 96, 1996 (Box 47, Folder 54)
    - Ray Davis, 1996 (Box 47, Folder 55)
    - Soviet Union and the Bomb, 1996 (Box 47, Folder 56)
    - My Life with Peierls, (n.d.) (Box 47, Folder 57)
    - S. S. Schweber physics history, (n.d.) (Box 47, Folder 58)
    - Feynman obit (Bethe), 1988 (Box 47, Folder 59)
    - Chandra Obituary, 1995 (Box 47, Folder 60)
    - Stu Shapiro, 1995 (Box 47, Folder 61)
    - Documentary on German A Bomb Project; Hein TV, early 1996, 1996 (Box 47, Folder 62)
    - Geo Gamow Symposium, Wash., 1996 (Box 47, Folder 63)
    - Hans Bethe Prize, 1996-1997 (Box 47, Folder 64)
    - Bethe: J. Robert Oppenheimer, 1997 (Box 47, Folder 65)
    - Misc. A-bomb notes, (n.d.) (Box 47, Folder 66)
    - Schweber: High Energy Physics, (n.d.) (Box 47, Folder 67)
    - Oral History: Arbatov, INF Treaty, USSR, 1991 (Box 47, Folder 68)
    - Peierls, 1994-1997 (Box 47, Folder 69)
    - Los Alamos Story 43-45; 28 Oct., 1996 (Box 47, Folder 70)
    - Interviews, 1998 (Box 47, Folder 71)
    - Physicists in Politics (Gottfried), 1998 (Box 47, Folder 72)
    - Lecture on History, (n.d.) (Box 47, Folder 73)
    - Feynman, Physics, 1994 (Box 47, Folder 74)
    - History, 1996-1997 (Box 47, Folder 75)
    - Decoding the Sun, 1998 (Box 47, Folder 76)
    - Heisenberg, (n.d.) (Box 47, Folder 77)
    - CNN Interview, 1999 (Box 47, Folder 78)
    - Bethe, Biography, 1974 (Box 47, Folder 79)
    - APS. Vugr: Rabi, (n.d.) (Box 47, Folder 80)
    - APS, 1991 (Box 47, Folder 81)
    - Sommerfeld's seminar (Bethe), 2000 (Box 47, Folder 82)
    - Sakharov's Ideas, Carson, 1992 (Box 47, Folder 83)
    - Pais, War Experiences, (n.d.) (Box 47, Folder 84)
    - History of Atomic Weapons, 1940, 1941 (Box 47, Folder 85)
    - Teller and the history of the H-bomb, 1955, 1982 (Box 47, Folder 86)
    - Winterberg, H-bomb, 1980, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Bethe comments, History of H-Bomb, 1982 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Oppy Security Hearings, 1982 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Port Chicago Explosion, 1993 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Russian A-bomb: Khariton, 1993 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Fitzpatrick, dissertation and Bethe interview, 1994-2000 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Qeensland, interview, 1998 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - H-bomb history: Teller, 1996 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Dirac, Schrödinger's cat, (n.d.) (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Misc History, 1992-1996 (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Riehl, 1994 (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - Washington APS, etc., 1995 (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - ABC /Interview 4/21/98, 1998 (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - Leo Szilard, 1998 (Box 48, Folder 14)
    - TV, 1998 (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - Photo, (n.d.) (Box 48, Folder 16)
    - Oldstone, Shelter Island, Pocono Conferences, 1949 (Box 48, Folder 17)
      See https://ecommons.cornell.edu/handle/1813/14146
    - 1953, 'Un-American Activities', 1949, 1953 (Box 48, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence on H-bomb w/ Bradbury, 1950-1953 (Box 48, Folder 19)
    - Edward Teller, 1950-1957 (Box 48, Folder 20)
    - VELA satellite, Sept. 22, 1979 event, 1979 (Box 48, Folder 21)
    - Hiroshima, 1995 (Box 48, Folder 22)
    - Mary Palevsky Granados, 1995-1997 (Box 48, Folder 23)
    - APS Centennial Mtg., 1998 (Box 48, Folder 24)
    - Leo Szilard's Ashes, 1998 (Box 48, Folder 25)
    - TV Interviews: ABC, NHR, Asahi Shimbun, 1998, 1999 (Box 48, Folder 26)
    - Atlanta, APS, 1999 (Box 48, Folder 27)
    - Celebrations of People, (n.d.) (Box 48, Folder 28)
    - Stan Woosley and Hans Photo, (n.d.) (Box 48, Folder 29)
    - Boltzman - Reis Eines Deutschen Professors ins Eldorado, 1925 (Box 48, Folder 30)
    - Old Los Alamos Correspondence, 1946 (Box 48, Folder 31)
    - Bethe, Nitrogen Bomb Comments, 1954 (Box 48, Folder 32)
    - Bethe - Biographical, 1957-1966 (Box 48, Folder 33)
    - NAS IG Bulletin, 1963 (Box 48, Folder 34)
    - National Academy of Sciences, 1963 (Box 48, Folder 35)
    - The Primal Flame, 1976 (Box 48, Folder 36)
    - Scientific Jokes, 1978 (Box 48, Folder 37)
    - Dyson and Lighthill, 1998 (Box 48, Folder 38)
    - Bethe 2000 FAS Planner, 2000 (Box 48, Folder 39)
    - Subramanyan Chandrasekhar, 1995 (Box 59, Folder 30)
    - Enrico Fermi in Rome, 2002 (Box 59, Folder 31)
    - Oppenheimer, 1967 (Box 59, Folder 32)
    - Three Tributes to Oppenheimer, 1967 (Box 59, Folder 33)
    - A-bomb, Bethe, 1976 (Box 59, Folder 34)
    - Ewald and Wilson tributes, 1988, 1992 (Box 59, Folder 35)
    - Tales of Los Alamos, 1953-1991 (Box 59, Folder 36)
    - History of Nuclear Reactions in Stars, Wash., 1987, 1987 (Box 59, Folder 37)
    - H-bomb History, 1982, 1983 (Box 59, Folder 38)
    - Weiner Interview, 1966 (Box 59, Folder 39)
    - Interview requests with correspondence, 2000 (Box 113, Folder 42)
    - Interview with Dieter Hoffman, 2004-2005 (Box 113, Folder 43)
    - Arms Control, 1999-2000 (Box 114, Folder 20)
    - Supernovas, 1996-1998 (Box 114, Folder 21)
    - Cosmology, 1998, 2000 (Box 114, Folder 22-24)
    - Test ban, 1999 (Box 114, Folder 25)
    - MBH calculations (Box 114, Folder 26)
    - Nuclear weapons, 2000 (Box 114, Folder 27)
    - Stowe, Vermont, 1961 (Box 114, Folder 28-29)
    - Los Alamos, 2002 (Box 115, Folder 1)
    - General AP (Box 115, Folder 2)
    - Missile defense, 2001 (Box 115, Folder 3)
    - ABM- Anti-missile, 2000 (Box 115, Folder 4-5)
    - Copenhagen, 1990s-2000 (Box 115, Folder 6-9)
    - J. Robert Oppenheimer clippings, 1954, 1967 (Box 115, Folder 27-31)
    - J. Robert Oppenheimer, 1954, 2000 (Box 116, Folder 1-3)
    - Bound collection of articles and clippings on Oppenheimer (Box 117)
    - Summation by Lloyd Garrison, in the matter of J. Robert Oppenheimer. Also photocopy of playbill and record for the play In the Matter of J. Robert Oppenheimer., 1954, 1969 (Box 117, Folder 3)
    - Bethe and Gerald Brown materials (Box 116, Folder 4-11)
    - Gerald Brown and others (Box 116, Folder 12-14)
    - Politics bulletin, 1955-1956 (Box 116, Folder 15)
    - ALAS, 1945 (Box 115, Folder 16)
    - USS Nautilus photos and articles (Box 117, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with famous signatures (Box 117, Folder 5)
      Including Jacob Javits, Hubert Humphrey, Adlai Stevenson, Dwight Eisenhower, and Oppenheimer
  - Subseries II. Manhattan Project
    Especially material on Los Alamos and Trinity.
    - Los Alamos Theoretical Division, 1945 (Box 48, Folder 40)
    - Talk: LA Challenges, (n.d.) (Box 48, Folder 41)
    - LA History, Carson Mark, (n.d.) (Box 48, Folder 42)
    - Manhattan Project, KGB, 1938-1945 (Box 48, Folder 43)
    - Manhattan Project, 1982-1991 (Box 48, Folder 44)
    - Manhattan Project, (n.d.) (Box 48, Folder 45)
    - Manhattan Project, 1994 (Box 48, Folder 46)
    - Story of Los Alamos, (n.d.) (Box 48, Folder 47)
    - Trinity test site maps, (n.d.) (Box 48, Folder 48)
    - Critical Masses and Multiplication Rates, R. Serber, 1945 (Box 48, Folder 49)
    - Answers to Questions on Manhattan Project, 1995 (Box 48, Folder 50)
    - Copies of Letters, Interviews, 1999 (Box 48, Folder 51)
    - Los Alamos Theoretical Division, 6th Anniversary, 2002 (Box 48, Folder 52)
    - Symposium on Manhattan Project, 2002 (Box 48, Folder 53)
    - Los Alamos During Oppenheimer Years, 1994 (Box 59, Folder 40)
  - Subseries III. Soviet and International Science and Intrigue
    Includes material on controversies surrounding Soviets, Germans and others. Includes several files on the Sudoplatov controversy, in which a former Soviet spy claimed that Oppenheimer and other prominent Manhattan Project participants had shared classified information with the Soviets. Also includes material on the controversy over whether the German physicist Heisenberg intentionally sabotaged Nazi efforts to create an atomic bomb, including discussion surrounding the Farm Hill Transcripts.
    - Soviet Science, 1978 (Box 48, Folder 54)
    - Sudoplatov 1A: Sci Am., 1994-1995 (Box 48, Folder 55)
    - Sudoplatov 1B: Kurchatov's digest of Fuchs information, 1993-1994 (Box 48, Folder 56)
    - Sudoplatov 1C: Op-Ed. Wash Post 27 May 94, 1994 (Box 48, Folder 57)
    - Sudoplatov 1D: July, 94, 1994 (Box 48, Folder 58)
    - Sudoplatov 1E: Jeremy Stone, 1994 (Box 48, Folder 59)
    - Sudoplatov 1F: Sunday Times, 1994 (Box 48, Folder 60)
    - Sudoplatov 1G: Halloway, Review in Nature, (n.d.) (Box 48, Folder 61)
    - Sudoplatov 1H: Holloway, Excerpts, (n.d.) (Box 48, Folder 62)
    - Sudoplatov 1I: Macrae, Johnny book, 1992 (Box 48, Folder 63)
    - Sudoplatov 2A: McNeil-Lehrer, National Review, 1994 (Box 48, Folder 64)
    - Sudoplatov 2B: Sudo. Talk at WHCU, 1994 (Box 48, Folder 65)
    - Sudoplatov 2C: Wash Post, McMillan, 1994 (Box 48, Folder 66)
    - Sudoplatov 2D: Sudo. Other Info., 1994 (Box 48, Folder 67)
    - Sudoplatov 2E: Sudo 3, NYT, Rhodes, 1994 (Box 48, Folder 68)
    - Sudoplatov 2F: Sudo. Bohr, Peirels, Teller, 1994 (Box 48, Folder 69)
    - Sudoplatov 2G: Holloway; Jeremy [Stone], 1994 (Box 48, Folder 70)
    - Sudoplatov 2H: Powers, Morrison, 1994 (Box 48, Folder 71)
    - Atomic Bomb, (n.d.) (Box 48, Folder 72)
    - Farm Hall, Bernstein article, 1944-1947 (Box 48, Folder 73)
    - Farm Hall, Heisenberg, 1945, 1991 (Box 48, Folder 74)
    - Heisenberg Reactor Concepts, 1984 (Box 48, Folder 75)
    - Farm Hall Talk, Powers corresp., 1990, 1992 (Box 48, Folder 76)
    - Farm Hall, Bernstein article, 1991 (Box 48, Folder 77)
    - Heisenberg, Walker, 1991-1993 (Box 48, Folder 78)
    - Heisenberg Lecture (by Bethe), 1992 (Box 48, Folder 79)
    - History of Russian Bomb, 1992 (Box 48, Folder 80)
    - Bulletin on Heisenberg, 1992 (Box 48, Folder 81)
    - Clemson U., Rhodes notes and ms., 1994 (Box 48, Folder 82)
    - Heisenberg diagram, Bore, 1994, 1995 (Box 48, Folder 83)
    - Bohr, Soviet relations, 1994-1996 (Box 48, Folder 84)
    - Russian Bomb Program, 1993, 1994 (Box 48, Folder 85)
    - Heisenberg, 1991 (Box 48, Folder 86)
    - Soviet Nuclear History (partial document), (n.d.) (Box 48, Folder 87)
    - Oberwolfach 1944-1964, 1998 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Killian, Soviet Science Conference, 1957 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Sakharov's Memoirs, (n.d.) (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Soviet Jews, 1972-1977 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Russian Cooperation, 1978 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Sakharov and Human Rights, 1979-1984 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Human Rights Watch, 1993 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Helsinki Watch, 1980 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Helsinki Watch Committee, 1980-1986 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Sakharov, 1980-1986 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Letter to Breshnev for Batovrin, 1981, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Frederick Seitz, book translation, 1988, 1994 (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - Kumakhov-Linhard-Uberall nomination, USSR, 1998 (Box 49, Folder 13)
    - Jeremy Stone, 1999 (Box 49, Folder 14)
    - Heisenberg Diagram, 2001 (Box 49, Folder 15)
    - The German Uranium Project, 2000 (Box 59, Folder 41)
    - Farm Hall, Bohr, Heisenberg, 1991, 1992 (Box 59, Folder 42)
    - Russian Money, 1991 (Box 59, Folder 43)
    - Soviet Science, 1962 (Box 59, Folder 44)
- Series VII. Certificates and Awards
  Includes special certificates and awards that Bethe received.
  - Personal Papers, List of Publications, 1934-1976 (Box 51, Folder 29)
  - Department of State, Geneva Talks, 1955 (Box 51, Folder 30)
  - Bethe - Biographical Material, 1958-1962 (Box 51, Folder 31)
  - Prometheus Scoiety, 1998 (Box 51, Folder 32)
  - Gleitsman Foundation, 2000 (Box 51, Folder 33)
  - LANL Medal (correspondence), 2001 (Box 51, Folder 34)
  - Fermi I Pioneers Certificate, 1990 (Box 51, Folder 35)
  - Bush Award, 1985 (Box 51, Folder 36)
  - Oersted Medal, 1993 (Box 51, Folder 37)
  - Who's Who in America, 41th Edition, 1980-1981 (Box 51, Folder 38)
  - AAAS Fellow, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 39)
  - Fermi prize materials, 1960-1969 (Box 112, Folder 27-29)
  - Various awards and certificates, 1935 (Box 112, Folder 30)
  - Enrico Fermis Award given by President John F. Kennedy and the Atomic Energy Commission, 1961-12-01
    Kept in wooden box in the Dept. of Physics in Clark Hall
  - Congratulations from Cornell University on Nobel Prize, 1967 (Box 119)
  - Albert Einstein Peace Prize plaque, 1992 (Box 119)
  - Oersted Award - certificate from American Association of Physics Teachers, 1993 (Box 119)
  - Certificate from the Board of Trustees of appreciation for sixty years at Cornell University, 1995 (Box 119)
  - "Cosmic Coincidence" (Mapcase-folder 1)
    Data obtained with NASA's Hubble Space Telescope and processed by John Bahcall, David Saxe and Donald Schneider
  - Painting "The Man and the Universe" by Francesco Vaccarone, 1986 (Mapcase-folder 1)
    Compliments of the International School of Physics "Enrico Fermi"
- Series VIII. Oversize
  Oversized material of varied type. Topics range from the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to old letters from Sommerfeld.
  - Distribution of Star Masses, 1978 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Atomic Energy Act of 1954, 1980, 1981 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - AMB Treaty and SDI, 1987 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Nuclear War Consequences, 1983 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Israel, 1977-1986 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Science and Foreign Affairs, 1959 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - TV, Canada, 1999 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1947-1955 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Sommerfeld: Letter, 1936 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Oppenheimer, Uncommon Sense, 1984 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Farm Hall Transcripts, 1945 (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Progressive' Article, 1976 (Box 52, Folder 12)
- Series IX. Multimedia
  - Subseries I. Videos
    - Hans Bethe answers and questions about supernovae MP division, Special Colloquium, August 8, 1989; V-8976 (Box 116)
    - The Greatest Mind Since Einstein, V-8977 (Box 116)
    - Loeb Historical Lecture, April 26, 1995; V-8978 (Box 116)
    - Hans Bethe at UCLA, February 10, 1989; V-8979 (Box 116)
    - A Conversation with Emeritus Professors Dr. Hans Bethe and Dr. Robert Wilson, V-8980 (Box 116)
    - A Conversation with Emeritus Professor Dr. Hans Bethe and Dr. Victor Weisskopf, V-8981 (Box 116)
    - An Evening with Hans Bethe: The German A-Bomb Project, V-8982 (Box 116)
    - The Quest for Tanne Tuva, V-8983 (Box 116)
    - Horizon- No Ordinary Genius, November 26, 1992; V-8984 (Box 116)
    - The Pleasure of Finding Things Out, V-8985 (Box 116)
    - Biography of v. Laue with PPE and autobiographical remarks, 1979; V-8986 (Box 116)
    - Unlabelled (Red Bomb?), V-8987 (Box 116)
    - NOVA: A Star is Born, 1987; V-8988 (Box 116)
    - Red Bomb, V-8989 (Box 116)
  - Subseries II. Tape Recordings
    - Bethe: Talk to FAS Members at Los Alamos, July 9, 1953; Tr-10675 (Box 116)
    - Bethe interview, 1962; Tr-10676 (Box 116)